Alex. Brown & Sons Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Alex. Brown & Sons Records1796-1908 (bulk 1796-1884)
MSS14019
Alex. Brown & Sons
circa 80,000 items 266 containers 51 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lettercopy and letterpress books (1802-1880), daybooks (1800-1867), cashbooks (1829-1876), ledgers (1796-1878), and other business records of the firm founded by Alexander Brown in Baltimore, Md., circa 1800 which grew from a mercantile business into an international banking house.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Brown, Alexander, 1764-1834.; Brown, Alexander, 1858-1949.; Brown, George Stewart, 1834-1890.; Brown, George, 1787-1859.; Brown, James, 1791-1877.; Brown, John A., 1788-1872.; Brown, Stewart, 1769-; Brown, William, Sir, 1784-1864.; Falls, Moore.
Organizations
Alex. Brown & Sons.; Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company.; Brown Brothers & Company.; Brown, Shipley & Co.; Falls & Brown.; Stewart Brown (Firm)
Subjects
Banks and banking, International.; Banks and banking--Maryland--Baltimore.; International finance.; Linen industry--Ireland.; Merchants--Maryland--Baltimore.; Merchants--Pennsylvania--Philadelphia.; Public utilities.; Shipbuilding.; Trading companies.
Places
United States--Economic conditions--19th century.; United States--History--19th century.; United States--Politics and government--19th century.; United States--Social life and customs--19th century.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The records of the firm of Alex. Brown & Sons were given to the Library of Congress in 1954 by Benjamin H. Griswold III on behalf of the firm.
Access and Restrictions
The records of Alex. Brown & Sons are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Microfilm
A microfilm edition of Containers 125, 198, and 242 is available on one reel. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division concerning availability for purchase or interlibrary loan. To promote preservation of the originals, researchers are required to consult the microfilm edition as available.
Organizational History
Date Event
1800 Firm established in Baltimore, Md., by Alexander Brown (1764-1834)
1804 Alexander Brown (1764-1834) organized Baltimore Water Co.
1810 William Brown (1784-1864) sent to London, England, to establish firm of Brown Shipley & Co.
1818 John A. Brown (1788-1872) sent to Philadelphia, Pa., to found Brown Brothers Harriman and Company
1825 James Brown (1791-1877) sent to New York to found firm of Brown Brothers & Co.
1827 Alexander Brown (1764-1834) helped organize Baltimore & Ohio Railroad Brown v. Maryland decided in favor of Alex. Brown & Sons
1834 Alexander Brown (born 1764) died George Brown (1787-1859) named senior partner
1839 Alex. Brown & Sons became separate banking concern
1859 George Stewart Brown (1834-1890) named head of Baltimore, Md., house
1890 Alexander Brown (1858-1949) named senior partner
1924 Benjamin Howell Griswold (1858-1949) named head of firm
1946 Alexander B. Griswold (1907- ) succeeded his father as senior partner
Scope and Content Note
The records of Alex. Brown & Sons span the years 1796-1908, with the bulk of the material dating from 1796 to 1884. Included are business records of successor companies, subsidiaries, and allied business. The records document the commercial and financial activities of Alexander Brown, his sons, and their successors, showing the development of their banking house in conjunction with extensive import-export operations, the building of ships and worldwide trade activities, and the building of the Baltimore & Ohio Railroad. They also reflect the company's change from a mercantile to an international banking house having connections with Brown, Shipley & Company of Liverpool, and with Brown Brothers & Company, of New York, Philadelphia, and Baltimore. The records are organized into the following series: Lettercopy Books, Letterpress Books, Daybooks, Cashbooks, Ledgers, Sterling Ledgers, Ledger Sight Bills, Journals, Sales Books, Waste Books, Accounts Current, Blotters, and Miscellany.
The firm of Alex. Brown & Sons was founded by Alexander Brown, an Irish immigrant who came to Baltimore in 1797 and engaged in the mercantile business as an importer of Irish linen. The records are largely confined to the operations of the firm's outlets in Baltimore, which served as the American headquarters for the firm's chain of offices from 1800 to 1840. Lettercopy and letterpress books generally provide a continuous, daily record of the branch's outgoing correspondence with other offices in the organization and with the branch's out-of-town customers from 1800 to 1879.
Letterbooks, in the collection contain detailed information concerning political, civil, and military affairs affecting the firm. The Lettercopy Books series, consisting of letters sent, includes records of the Falls and Brown Company, 1803-1804, and of Campbell McIlvaine & Company, 1830-1837. The Letterpress Books series is organized into three subseries. Set A includes records similar to those in the Lettercopy Books series and is distinguished from them chiefly by the copying method. Set B is comprised of letterpress copies of letters sent to Brown Shipley & Company, London, England. The letterpress copies in Set C are of letters sent to Brown Brothers & Company, Boston, New York, and Philadelphia offices.
The collection also includes financial records in a variety of formats. Daybooks are daily journals of business transactions in the order of their occurrence. Cashbooks record money received and paid out, showing date of transaction, name of customer or client, description of the transaction, and amounts received and expended. Ledgers contain postings to accounts receivable and accounts payable; they include ledgers of Falls & Brown, Baltimore, 1796-1810. Sterling Ledgers contain postings to accounts receivable and accounts payable of Alex. Brown & Sons sterling operations. Ledger Sight Bills contain a record of journal postings by bill number. Journals contain daily entries from daybooks and blotters. Sales Books appear to be logs of customer sales. Waste Books are daily journals of business transactions in the order of their occurrence; one book is from Stewart Brown, Philadelphia, and Falls & Brown, Baltimore. Accounts Current appear to be summaries of accounts receivable and accounts payable. Account entries include account name, transaction date, and description. Blotters are daily journals of business transactions.
The Miscellany series includes journals and ledgers of the Union Railroad Company sinking fund, credit rating and statements books, minute books of the Aransas Pass Harbor Company of which Brown and Sons Company was a bondholder and trustee, and of the Female Orphan Asylum, Baltimore. Also in the series is a book containing signatures of persons authorized to conduct business with Brown & Sons Company.
The collection also includes records of other Brown family firms, such as the firms of Stewart Brown, of Philadelphia, an older brother of Alexander Brown, 22 April 1796- 30 May 1797; and of Moore Falls and Stewart Brown of the firm of Falls & Brown, of Baltimore, 1797-1810. These records are not necessarily noted specifically in the descriptions below
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in thirteen series:
Lettercopy Books, 1802-1863
Letterpress Books, 1841-1880
Daybooks, 1800-1867
Cashbooks, 1829-1876
Ledgers, 1796-1878
Sterling Ledgers, 1867-1876
Ledger Sight Bills, 1852-1884
Journals, 1824-1848
Sales Books, 1824-1838
Waste Books, 1796-1806
Accounts Current, 1826-1881
Blotters, 1805-1839
Miscellany, 1802-1908
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm81014019
Container List
- Lettercopy Books, 1802-1863 (Box 1-40)
  Copies of letters sent. Some volumes contain an alphabetical index of correspondents.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Dec. 1802-May 1804 (Box 1)
  - Jan. 1803-Aug. 1804 (Falls & Brown) (Box 2)
  - Dec. 1810-May 1814 (Box 3)
  - Apr. 1818-Apr. 1819 (Box 4)
  - Apr. 1819-May 1820 (Box 5)
  - June 1819-May 1821 (Box 6)
  - Jan. 1822-Dec. 1823 (Box 7)
  - Dec. 1823-Dec. 1825 (Box 8)
  - Nov. 1823-Mar. 1831 (Box 9)
  - Dec. 1825-May 1828 (Box 10)
  - July 1826-July 1830 (Box 11)
  - Mar. 1828-May 1831 (Box 12)
  - July 1830-June 1832 (Campbell McIlvain & Co.) (Box 13)
  - Mar. 1831-Jan. 1836 (Box 14)
  - May 1831-May 1833 (Box 15)
  - June 1832-Jan. 1834 (Campbell McIlvain & Co.) (Box 16)
  - Dec. 1833-Sept. 1835 (Box 17)
  - Jan. 1835-Nov. 1837 (Campbell McIlvain & Co.) (Box 18)
  - Sept. 1835-Jan. 1838 (Box 19)
  - Jan. 1836-Aug. 1839 (Box 20)
  - Jan. 1838-Apr. 1840 (Box 21)
  - Aug. 1839-Apr. 1844 (Box 22)
  - Apr. 1840-Sept. 1842 (Box 23)
  - Oct. 1842-Oct. 1845 (Box 24)
  - Apr. 1844-Dec. 1847 (Box 25)
  - Oct. 1845-May 1851 (Box 26)
  - Dec. 1847-May 1850 (Box 27)
  - June 1850-Sept. 1853 (Box 28)
  - May 1851-Apr. 1852 (Box 29)
  - Jan. 1853-Mar. 1853 (Box 30)
  - Mar. 1853-Sept. 1854 (Box 31)
  - Sept. 1853-Apr. 1856 (Box 32)
  - Apr. 1854-Jan. 1856 (Box 33)
  - June 1856-Oct. 1857 (Box 34)
  - May 1856-Oct. 1859 (Box 35)
  - Oct. 1856-July 1859 (Box 36)
  - July 1859-Feb. 1861 (Box 37)
  - Oct. 1859-Apr. 1863 (Box 38)
  - Mar. 1861-Jan. 1863 (Box 39)
  - Jan. 1863-May 1863 (Box 40)
- Letterpress Books, 1841-1880 (Box 41-124)
  - Set A, 1841-1879 (Box 41-78)
    Letterpress copies of letters sent. Some volumes contain an alphabetical index of correspondents.
    - July 5, 1841-Mar. 8, 1845 (Box 41)
    - Mar. 2, 1865-Mar. 2, 1868 (Box 42)
    - Dec. 19, 1867-July 15, 1868 (Box 43)
    - July 16, 1868-Mar. 31, 1869 (Box 44)
    - Mar. 31, 1869-Oct. 9, 1869 (Box 45)
    - Oct. 9, 1869-Mar. 3, 1870 (Box 46)
    - Mar. 4, 1870-July 5, 1870 (Box 47)
    - July 6, 1870-Nov. 21, 1870 (Box 48)
    - Nov. 21, 1870-Feb. 17, 1871 (Box 49)
    - Feb. 17, 1871-June 16, 1871 (Box 50)
    - June 16, 1871-Nov. 11, 1871 (Box 51)
    - Nov. 13, 1871-Feb. 28, 1872 (Box 52)
    - Feb. 24, 1872-June 27, 1872 (Box 53)
    - June 27, 1872-Oct. 18, 1872 (Box 54)
    - Oct.. 17, 1872-Feb. 1, 1873 (Box 55)
    - Feb. 1, 1873-May 12, 1873 (Box 56)
    - May 13, 1873-Aug. 16, 1873 (Box 57)
    - Aug. 18, 1873-Nov. 10, 1873 (Box 58)
    - Nov. 10, 1873-Feb. 2, 1874 (Box 59)
    - Feb. 3, 1874-May 19, 1874 (Box 60)
    - May 20, 1874-Sept. 10, 1874 (Box 61)
    - Sept. 11, 1874-Dec. 30, 1874 (Box 62)
    - Dec. 31, 1874-Apr. 19, 1875 (Box 63)
    - Apr. 20, 1875-July 28, 1875 (Box 64)
    - July 29, 1875-Oct. 26, 1875 (Box 65)
    - Oct. 26, 1875-Jan. 3, 1876 (Box 66)
    - Jan. 3, 1876-Mar. 15, 1876, (The volume for the period from Mar. 16 to June 16, 1876 was not sent.) (Box 67)
    - June 17, 1876-Oct. 9, 1876 (Box 68)
    - Oct. 9, 1876-Jan. 27, 1877 (Box 69)
    - Jan. 27, 1877-May 14, 1877 (Box 70)
    - May 15, 1877-Sept. 3, 1877 (Box 71)
    - Sept. 3, 1877-Dec. 22, 1877 (Box 72)
    - Dec. 22, 1877-Apr. 5, 1878 (Box 73)
    - Apr. 5, 1878-July 12, 1878 (Box 74)
    - July 12, 1878-Nov. 4, 1878 (Box 75)
    - Nov. 4, 1878-Feb. 21, 1879 (Box 76)
    - Feb. 21, 1879-June 18, 1879 (Box 77)
    - June 18, 1879-Oct. 27, 1879 (Box 78)
  - Set B, 1863-1879 (Box 79-102)
    Letterpress copies of letters sent to Brown Shipley & Co., London, England. Some volumes contain an alphabetical index of correspondents.
    - May 22, 1863-Dec. 30, 1864 (Box 79)
    - Jan. 4, 1867-Oct. 14, 1867 (Box 80)
    - Oct. 12, 1867-Nov. 24, 1868 (Box 81)
    - Nov. 24, 1868-July 2, 1869 (Box 82)
    - July 6, 1869-Jan. 28, 1870 (Box 83)
    - Feb. 1, 1870-Sept. 2, 1870 (Box 84)
    - Sept. 6, 1870-Mar. 7, 1871 (Box 85)
    - Mar. 7, 1871-Aug. 15, 1871 (Box 86)
    - Aug. 15, 1871-Jan. 23, 1872 (Box 87)
    - Jan. 23, 1872-June 14, 1872 (Box 88)
    - June 14, 1872-Nov. 8, 1872 (Box 89)
    - Nov. 8, 1872-Mar. 19, 1873 (Box 90)
    - Mar. 31, 1873-Aug. 12, 1873 (Box 91)
    - Aug. 12, 1873-Feb. 6, 1874 (Box 92)
    - Feb. 6, 1874-Aug. 17, 1874 (Box 93)
    - Aug. 7, 1874-Feb. 19, 1875 (Box 94)
    - Feb. 23, 1875-Sept. 29, 1875 (Box 95)
    - Sept. 29, 1875-Apr. 12, 1876 (Box 96)
    - Apr. 12, 1876-Oct. 31, 1876 (Box 97)
    - Oct. 31, 1876-May 29, 1877 (Box 98)
    - May 29, 1877-Jan. 16, 1878 (Box 99)
    - Jan. 18, 1878-Aug. 21, 1879 (Box 100)
    - Aug. 23, 1878-Mar. 17, 1879 (Box 101)
    - Mar. 17, 1879-Oct. 6, 1879 (Box 102)
  - Set C, 1865-1880 (Box 103-124)
    Letterpress copies of letters sent to Brown Brothers & Co., Boston, Mass., New York, N.Y., and Philadelphia, Pa., offices. Some volumes contain an alphabetical index of correspondents.
    - June 21, 1865-May 21, 1866 (Box 103)
    - May 23, 1866-June 15, 1867 (Box 104)
    - Jan. 2, 1867-Nov. 15, 1867 (Box 105)
    - Nov. 16, 1867-Aug. 1, 1868 (Box 106)
    - Aug. 1, 1868-Apr. 26, 1869 (Box 107)
    - Apr. 24, 1869-Nov. 23, 1869 (Box 108)
    - Nov. 24, 1869-Aug. 4, 1870 (Box 109)
    - Aug. 4, 1870-Apr. 18, 1871 (Box 110)
    - Apr. 18, 1871-Jan. 2, 1872 (Box 111)
    - Jan. 3, 1872-Sept. 26, 1872 (Box 112)
    - Sept. 27, 1872-May 12, 1873 (Box 113)
    - May 13, 1873-Dec. 10, 1873 (Box 114)
    - Dec. 11, 1873-July 29, 1874 (Box 115)
    - July 30, 1874-Mar. 19, 1875 (Box 116)
    - Mar. 20, 1875-Oct. 26, 1875 (Box 117)
    - Oct. 26, 1875-May 5, 1876 (Box 118)
    - May 6, 1876-Dec. 14, 1876 (Box 119)
    - Dec. 15, 1876-Aug. 21, 1877 (Box 120)
    - Aug. 22, 1877-Apr. 9, 1878 (Box 121)
    - Apr. 10, 1878-Oct. 23, 1878 (Box 122)
    - Oct. 24, 1878-July 14, 1879 (Box 123)
    - July 15, 1879-Mar. 31, 1880 (Box 124)
- Daybooks, 1800-1867 (Box 125-162)
  Daily journals of business transactions in the order of their occurrence showing store location, date of transaction, folio number, name of customer or client, nature of transaction, description of merchandise, quantities, and amounts received and expended.
  Arranged chronologically by date of business transaction.
  - 1800-1804, This volume available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 10,830 (Box 125)
  - 1806-1807 (Box 126)
  - 1809-1810 (Box 127)
  - 1813-1816 (Box 128)
  - 1816-1817 (Box 129)
  - 1818-1819 (Box 130)
  - 1824-1825 (Box 131)
  - 1825-1827 (Box 132)
  - 1828-1830 (Box 133)
  - 1830-1832 (Box 134)
  - 1832-1834 (Box 135)
  - 1833-1837 (Box 136)
  - 1834-1836 (Box 137)
  - 1836-1837 (Box 138)
  - 1837-1838 (Box 139)
  - 1838-1840 (Box 140)
  - 1840-1841 (Box 141)
  - 1841-1842 (Box 142)
  - 1842-1843 (Box 143)
  - 1843-1845 (Box 144)
  - 1845-1846 (Box 145)
  - 1846-1848 (Box 146)
  - 1848-1849 (Box 147)
  - 1849-1851 (Box 148)
  - 1851-1854 (Box 149)
  - 1852-1853 (Box 150)
  - 1852-1855 (Box 151)
  - 1853-1854 (Box 152)
  - 1854-1856 (Box 153)
  - 1855-1858 (Box 154)
  - 1856-1858 (Box 155)
  - 1858-1860 (Box 156)
  - 1858-1862 (Box 157)
  - 1860-1864 (Box 158)
  - 1860-1863 (Box 159)
  - 1862-1866 (Box 160)
  - 1863-1866 (Box 161)
  - 1866-1867 (Box 162)
- Cashbooks, 1829-1876 (Box 163-197)
  Record of money received and paid out showing date of transaction, name of customer or client, transaction description, and amounts received and expended.
  - 1829-1831, 1833-1835 (Box 163-164)
  - 1835-1837 (Box 165-166)
  - 1838-1840 (Box 167-8)
  - 1840-1842 (Box 169-70)
  - 1842-1846 (Box 171-2)
  - 1843-1847 (Box 173-4)
  - 1847-1849 (Box 175-6)
  - 1849-1852 (Box 177-8)
  - 1850-1870 (Box 179)
  - 1852-1853 (Box 180)
  - 1853-1856 (Box 181)
  - 1856-1859 (Box 182)
  - 1859-1861 (Box 183)
  - 1860-1863 (Box 184)
  - 1861-1865 (Box 185)
  - 1863-1865 (Box 186)
  - 1865-1866 (Box 187)
  - 1863-1867 (Box 188)
  - 1866-1868 (Box 189)
  - 1867-1868 (Box 190)
  - 1868-1869 (Box 191)
  - 1868-1869 (Box 192)
  - 1869-1871 (Box 193)
  - 1871-1872 (Box 194)
  - 1872-1873 (Box 195)
  - 1873-1875 (Box 196)
  - 1875-1876 (Box 197)
- Ledgers, 1796-1878 (Box 198-222)
  Volumes contain postings to accounts receivable and accounts payable. Account entries include account name, transaction date, description of transaction, folio number, and amounts credited and debited. Some volumes contain alphabetical indexes of account, customer, and client names.
  - 1796-1810 (Falls & Brown, Baltimore, Md.), This volume available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 10,830 (Box 198)
  - 1821-1824 (Box 199)
  - 1825-1833 (Box 200)
  - 1826-1829 (Box 201)
  - 1833-1839 (Box 202)
  - 1837-1838 (Box 203)
  - 1838-1843 (Box 204)
  - 1843-1849 (Box 205)
  - 1849-1852 (Box 206)
  - 1852-1854 (Box 207)
  - 1852-1855 (Box 208)
  - 1853-1868 (Box 209)
  - 1854-1858 (Box 210)
  - 1854-1856 (Box 211)
  - 1857-1859 (Box 212)
  - 1858-1861 (Box 213)
  - 1861-1866 (Box 214)
  - 1867-1868 (Box 215)
  - 1868-1870 (Box 216)
  - 1870-1871 (Box 217)
  - 1871-1872 (Box 218)
  - 1872-1873 (Box 219)
  - 1873-1874 (Box 220)
  - 1874-1875 (Box 221)
  - 1875-1878 (Box 222)
- Sterling Ledgers, 1867-1876 (Box 223-226)
  Volumes are labeled "supplementary sterling ledgers" and appear to contain postings to accounts receivable and accounts payable of Alex. Brown & Sons sterling operations. Entries include account name, transaction date, description of transaction, folio number, and amounts credited and debited. Some volumes contain alphabetical indexes of account, customer, and client names.
  - 1867-1868 (Box 223)
  - 1870-1872 (Box 224)
  - 1872-1873 (Box 225)
  - 1873-1876 (Box 226)
- Ledger Sight Bills, 1852-1884 (Box 227-230)
  Contains a record of journal postings by bill number. Entries include transaction date, bill number, date paid, amount paid, and folio number.
  Arranged chronologically by business transaction date.
  - 1852-1856 (Box 227)
  - 1856-1865 (Box 228)
  - 1868-1879 (Box 229)
  - 1868-1884 (Box 230)
- Journals, 1824-1848 (Box 231-237)
  Volumes contain daily entries from daybooks and blotters. Entries include folio number, date of transaction, transaction description, and amounts credited or debited.
  - 1826-1829 (Box 231)
  - 1829-1832 (Box 232)
  - 1832-1834 (Box 233)
  - 1834-1835 (Box 234)
  - 1835-1838 (Box 235)
  - 1837, Apr.-Sept. (Box 236)
  - 1848 (Box 237)
- Sales Books, 1824-1838 (Box 238-241)
  Volumes appear to be logs of customer sales. Entries include folio number, date of transaction, name of customer, description of merchandise, quantities purchased, and amount of money received.
  - 1824-1832 (Box 238)
  - 1826-1836 (Box 239)
  - 1830-1834 (Box 240)
  - 1832-1838 (Box 241)
- Waste Books, 1796-1806 (Box 242-243)
  Daily journals of business transactions in the order of their occurrence. Entries for each transaction include folio number, date, nature of transaction, name of customer or client, and amounts received and expended.
  - Apr. 1796-Dec.1806 (Stewart Brown, Philadelphia, Pa., and Falls & Brown, Baltimore, Md.), This volume available only on microfilm. Shelf no. 10,830 (Box 242)
  - Oct. 1796-Dec. 1802 (Box 243)
- Accounts Current, 1826-1881 (Box 244-254)
  Volumes appear to be summaries of accounts receivable and accounts payable. Account entries include account name, transaction date, description of transaction, and amounts credited and debited. Some volumes contain alphabetical indexes of account, customer, and client names.
  - 1826-1834 (Box 244)
  - 1826-1838 (Box 245)
  - 1824-1838 (Box 246)
  - 1830-1842 (Box 247)
  - 1842-1847 (Box 248)
  - 1858-1866 (Box 249)
  - 1871-1872 (Box 250)
  - 1872-1873 (Box 251)
  - 1873-1874 (Box 252)
  - 1877-1879 (Box 253)
  - 1879-1881 (Box 254)
- Blotters, 1805-1839 (Box 255-258)
  - 1805-1806 (Box 255)
  - 1821-1823 (Box 256)
  - 1823-1824 (Box 257)
  - 1838-1839 (Box 258)
- Miscellany, 1802-1908 (Box 259-266)
  - Union Railroad Company Sinking Fund Journals and Ledgers, 1870-1886 (Box 259-261)
    Journals and ledgers for ground rent accounts held by trustees of the sinking fund of the Union Railroad Co., Baltimore, Md. Volume entries include date of transaction, account number, description of transaction, and amounts debited and credited.
    Volumes are arranged as journals and ledgers and chronologically therein.
    - Journal, 1871-1886 (Box 259)
    - Ledger, 1871-1872 (Box 260)
    - Ground rents, 1870-1875 (Box 261)
  - Credit Rating Book, undated (Box 262)
    Single volume denoting credit worthiness of customers and clients. Entries show date, customer or client name, and opinion concerning ability to pay, business practices, and reliability.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of customer or client.
  - Statements Book No. 9, 1899-1900 (Box 263)
    Letterpress copies of customers' statements of account containing date, customer name and address, description of merchandise purchased, quantities, and amounts credited and debited to account. Volume also contains weekly financial statements of Alex. Brown & Sons sterling operations and an alphabetical index of customers.
  - Aransas Pass Harbor Company Minute Book, 1897-1908 (Box 264)
    Contains minutes of meetings and copies of resolutions adopted by the board of trustees of the Aransas Pass Harbor Co., Aransas Pass, Tex., of which Brown & Sons Co. was a bondholder and trustee. Laid in are correspondence, resolutions, notes, lists, and agreements concerning acquisition of Aransas Harbor City & Improvement Co., Aransas Pass, Tex.
  - Female Orphan Asylum Minute Book, 1802-1857 (Box 265)
    Single volume containing minutes of meetings of the board of directors of the Female Orphan Asylum, Baltimore, Md. Also included are financial reports and a newspaper clipping concerning the founding of the organization.
  - Signature Book, circa 1871-1888 (Box 266)
    Contains signatures of persons authorized to conduct business with Brown & Sons Co. and includes letters of introduction, business cards, receipts, and signatures cut and pasted from other documents. Items entered alphabetically by name of customer or client, although some entries are not in proper order.